#### MD.IFTEKHAR AHMAD Mob No. +971509753078

Email: <a href="mailto:iftekhardxb@gmail.com">iftekhardxb@gmail.com</a></a>
Visa Status: Employment Visa



#### **Summary**

Bachelor in **Computer Science Engineering** with total **7 years of Experience** in the field of **IT** (**Information Technology**) in the area of **Technical Support Engineering & Datacenter Operation.** Strong operational, communication and presentation skills with good academic record throughout.

#### Education

Centurion Institute of Technology, Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India B. Tech Degree — 2008 - 2012

Completed B. Tech in Computer Science Engineering having CGPA 6.28 (62%) under Biju Patnaik University of Technology, Orissa, India.

# Work Experience

IT System Engineer (CNS Department)
Enova by Veolia, Sharjah International Airport, UAE
March 2016 - Present

#### **Main Responsibilities:**

- 1. Responsible for second & third-level support for all server & Network related issues.
- 2. Participated in complete system builds, upgrades, migrations and patch management.
- 3. Maintained and managed Domain Name Service for Active Directory (AD) enterprise.
- 4. Managed Group Policy Objects (GPOs) throughout the Active Directory enterprise.
- 5. Configuring Cisco Routers, Switches, Modems and Firewalls, Configuring VLANs.
- 6. Administered change management related to server upgrades and software installation.
- 7. Design and implement security systems and redundant backups to maintain data safety.
- 8. Install, configure, monitor and troubleshoot flight information display (FIDS) network, SITA DCS System and data communication software and hardware like ATB, BTP, BGR
- 9. Analyze, design, configure, and support airport operational and enterprise systems that improve business efficiency and productivity through best practices.
- 10. Maintaining ILS, VCCS, SITA DCS Server, FIDS Server, AWOS Server, AFTN Server, Ricochet System, CCTV Server, Public Address System in Datacenter.
- 11. Coordinate with suppliers for IT materials delivery on time.
- 12. Ensure that the deployed architecture for infrastructure, servers, PCs and peripherals meets the service level Agreement (SLA) requirements in terms of expected availability, capacity, continuity, security, performance and reliability and taking responsibility for escalation to ensure it achieve the KPI's target.
- 13. Good knowledge in ITSM & managing ITIL Service Operation process, IT infrastructure Operation, Application Support and Implementation of IT Service Desk tools in Enterprise.

IT System Administrator Key Business Group for Investment LLC, Dubai, UAE Nov 2014 – Jan 2016

Assistant System Engineer Neologix Software Solutions, India April 2012 – Sept 2014

#### Project Handled

- 1. EATC (Emergency Air Traffic Control Tower) Complete Setup, Sharjah Airport
  Team member of ATC-ST CNS/ATM systems like new VCCS configuration, GPS clock, VHF
  standby radio & ambient voice capturing system installation, AWOS & ILS RCSI Installation
- 2. New SITA & FIDS system installation in Sharjah Airport Gate Expansion Project.
- 2. Installation of New Jotron TA 76XX Transmitter, RA 7203X Receiver, RCMS
- 3. Developed application "Metrological Reporting System" for Department of Civil Aviation,
- 4. Developed application "Flight Information Display System (FIDS)", Sharjah Intl Airport.

#### Domain Skills

IT Skills: Hardware and Networking, OSI Model Layers, LAN/WAN, VLAN, TCP/IP, CISCO switch and router config., Cabling, Fiber Optic, Windows server 2008,2012, AD, DNS, DHCP, MS Exchange, Virtualization, Firewall, SAN, Backup & Recovery, Server Infrastructure (HP, Dell), NTP Server Datacenter operation, CCTV, Service Level Agreement(SLA), ITIL, ITSM, Problem, Incident & Change Management

#### **Training**

- 1. Air Traffic Safety Electronic Personnel (ATSEP) Level I Certified at Sharjah Intl Airport.
- 2. Cisco Networking Fundamentals (CCNA Exploration) Certified
- 3. CISCO Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Certified
- 4. Microsoft Certified Solution Associate (MCSA) External Training
- 5. ITIL Foundation V3. External Training

## Personal Profile

Father's name: Md. Abujaher Shah <u>Passport Details</u>:

D.O.B: 13th January 1991 Passport No: K4992853
Nationality: Indian Date of Issue: 30/04/2013
Sex: Male Date of Expiry: 29/04/2023

Marital Status: Married Religion: Islam

Language: English, Urdu, Hindi UAE Driving License: In Final Process

### Declaration

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Date :

Place : Sharjah, UAE Signature: Md. Iftekhar Ahmad